# Dario Curreri

dariocurr@gmail.com

dario curr. github.io



Throughout my studies and work experiences, I have honed my problem solving ability, developed several skills, faced fast-paced environments.

I am a contributor to many open source projects: I firmly believe that collaboration is the key to innovation

## Experience

#### DevOps & Technical Product Owner @ hiop

Oct 2021 - Today

- Co-creator of several components that led to the company's flagship product: an high-performance data processing mesh platform that enables DaC, quickly high-value data provision and data-driven decision making
- Co-creator of an HPC infrastructure on which relies real-time AI-based applications
- Designer and maintainer of company's CI/CD pipelines
- Creator and maintainer of several libraries on which the company's codebase relies
- Co-led growth, training and knowledge sharing among the team, which increased from 5 to 15 people

## Full Stack Developer @ CNR's Institute of Biophysics

Dec 2020 - Aug 2021

Collaborator involved in the *Human Brain Project* with the aim of developing a Python and JS-based web application named *NeuroFeatureExtract* to analyse electrophysiological features

#### Bioinformatics Trainee @ ISMETT

May 2021 - Jul 2021

Practitioner on efficient algorithms and technologies to analise biological sequences represented in FASTA format, as part of a university internship project

## Collaborator of ML Research Project @ UNINA

Nov 2019 - Mar 2020

Research project with the aim of developing a Python-based ML fuzzy classifier to diagnose celiac disease in Sicilian and Maltese children

## Full Stack Developer Trainee @ Informamuse

Jan 2019 - Mar 2019

Web Developer as part of a university internship project

#### Education

#### Double Master in Computer Science @ UNIPA & UGE

Sep 2019 - Oct 2021

Double Master achieved cum laude with final thesis about RDF data and columnar formats

ECTS: 120/120 GPA: 29.29/30

#### Bachelor in Computer Science @ UNIPA

Sep 2016 - Aug 2019

Bachelor achieved cum laude with final thesis about suffix array data structure

ECTS: 186/180 GPA: 29.00/30

## Erasmus Exchange @ ELTE

Sep 2018 - Jan 2019

Outstanding study experience which gave the opportunity to improve a vast set of skills

Others		Publication	
CMM Pre-doctoral Research School	Aug 2020	The EBRAINS NeuroFeatureExtract: An Online	
ESS Information Science School	Set 2019	Resource for the Extraction of Neural Activity Features	
Scientfic High School Diploma	2012 - 2016	From Electrophysiological Data	

#### Skills

Certifications	Languages	Workflow
AWS: Practitioner, Developer	Italian: native speaker	Bash, Git, Docker, CI/CD
Data Science	English: B2	Rust, Python, Java, Scala, C
GCP: Digital Leader	French: A2	AWS, GCP